<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>1 per Week</title>
    <description>Once a week we publish articles that help you make your life easier using iOS and Mac apps in various situations.</description>
    <link>http://1perweek.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://1perweek.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 17:08:54 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2015 17:08:54 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>iPhone is your DSLR</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;capture-it&quot;&gt;Capture it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The native camera app is getting better and better every year and it’s completely sufficient for quick shots. However, if you want more manual control, there is still room for other apps. Right now I am a big fan of &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/r8K&quot;&gt;Manual&lt;/a&gt; ($1.99). Its name says it all. It brings functions we know from DSLRs to your iPhone. You can, of course, shoot with full automatic mode, but the beauty of &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/r8K&quot;&gt;Manual&lt;/a&gt; lies in its manual mode. Setting exposure value, shutter speed, focus, sensitivity or white balance is easy as pie. You don’t have to be a professional photographer to enjoy using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cw4/cw4-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enhance-it&quot;&gt;Enhance it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shooting a picture isn’t the end, it’s actually the beginning. Every photo we make can be enhanced right in the iPhone. The most comprehensive and intuitive app I know is &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/1aOV&quot;&gt;Camera+&lt;/a&gt; ($2.99). It offers all necessary functions for more demanding users who want to tweak their photos to perfection. Straightening, sharpening, saturation and many more. You name a function and &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/1aOV&quot;&gt;Camera+&lt;/a&gt; has it. For the other, it offers so called scenes which automatically modify the picture to your desire. You can choose concert, beach, scenery, night and dozen more according to your wish. Add inexhaustible range of filters and frames and you have a must-have photo app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cw4/cw4-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;print-it&quot;&gt;Print it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You have captured your life moments and you have also added great filters and effects. Now you just need to get them printed! I have been looking for such app for a long time without success. Couple weeks ago it changed. I found &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/2hJn&quot;&gt;Photolane&lt;/a&gt; (free). It lets you create beautiful photo books in few simple steps. Although the process of creating the book could be a bit friendlier and easier to use, it’s still simple enough for everyone. And the result is definitely worth it. The book costs $40 and has 32 pages with up to 100 photos printed in stunning quality. You can rely completely on the app, or you can select layout for each page, add texts or crop photos. I have seen many so-called professional photo books for double the price, but they don’t stand a chance compared to my book from &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/2hJn&quot;&gt;Photolane&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cw4/cw4-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://1perweek.com/posts/4-2015</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1perweek.com/posts/4-2015</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Driving better</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-there-safely&quot;&gt;Get there safely&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All drivers know that the most important thing on driving is to get to our destination safely. There are tons of advanced driver assistance systems in new cars to help us. However, you don’t have to throw in the towel, if you don’t have them in your car.
What you need is an app called &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/2hMA&quot;&gt;iOnRoad&lt;/a&gt; ($4.99). It helps you keep a safe following distance and avoid out of lane wandering.  You only need to mount your iPhone on the dashboard and the app does the rest. It will warn you every time you get too close to the car in front of you or whenever your car starts to leave the lane. It might seem unnecessary for a daily commute, but the contrary is the case. You know every inch of the route and you could drive with your eyes closed. You pay less and less attention to the situation around. This is the moment when iOnRoad is a big help and a potential life saver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cw3/cw3-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drive-where-you-need-to&quot;&gt;Drive where you need to&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting safely to our destination isn’t the only concern we have while driving. We usually want to get there as soon as possible. There are navigation apps to help us with that. I have tested all offline navigations in the app store and also Google and Apple Maps. Some of them were good, some of them worse. Right now I am driving with Sygic (&lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/48zT&quot;&gt;Europe&lt;/a&gt;, $49.99| &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/FEb&quot;&gt;North America&lt;/a&gt;, $39.99) and I find it the best so far. It has all the functions you would expect from a navigation app including very good live traffic based on TomTom data and very accurate ETA. On top you can buy a blackbox feature which records and saves video when an accident happens or additional celebrity voices. Mr. Burns from The Simpsons is a funny co-pilot! Over the time I got used to use Sygic also during my daily commute to help me avoid heavy traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cw3/cw3-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;find-a-parking-space&quot;&gt;Find a parking space&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest challenge sometimes starts when you get to your destination and you need to find an available parking space. To help me with that I have been using &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/11ZO&quot;&gt;Parkopedia&lt;/a&gt; (free) for a while and I am completely satisfied with it. Obviously, it cannot help you find a parking space on the street but it covers a vast number of parking lots and many of them have also real-time availability info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cw3/cw3-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://1perweek.com/posts/3-2015</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1perweek.com/posts/3-2015</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Day full of skiing</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;check-theweather&quot;&gt;Check the weather&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve all skied in various weather conditions and I think we can agree that weather is one of the crucial aspects that affect the level of your skiing enjoyment. After packing your gear the second most important thing you need to do before you go is to check the weather forecast. If you had forgotten to do that before you called your friends and arranged the trip, do it now. It’s painful to cancel the trip due to weather right after you have organized it, but it’s still better than to stand in the parking lot in pouring rain the next day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a big amount of weather apps in the App Store and they all give you the basic information. However, if you want a bit more than these simple functions (and you should), go for &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/37V3&quot;&gt;WeatherPro&lt;/a&gt; ($2.99). Its predictions are accurate and detailed including weather maps with precipitations, cloud coverage, air pressure and temperature. It can help you to select the resort with the best weather. I’ve been using it for years when planning my skiing trips and it hasn’t ever let me down. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cw2/cw2-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know that the weather can change any minute in the mountains. Especially if you are in a larger resort it can take you easily an hour to get to your car.  To avoid encountering bad weather while on the summit I regularly use &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/3McH&quot;&gt;MeteoEarth&lt;/a&gt; ($2.99). It shows current status and future development of all necessary weather values in a nice layout. It only takes a while to check it while going uphill on a chair-lift. This few seconds helped me plenty of times to get back down just before a snowstorm hit the hill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cw2/cw2-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;locate-your-friends&quot;&gt;Locate your friends&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you go skiing with your friends, you can be pretty sure that at one time, your group will split. Someone needs a cigarette break, another one needs to use the restrooms and other want to grab some food in the restaurant. For that reason I am using Apple’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/19yS&quot;&gt;Find My Friends&lt;/a&gt; (free) every time I’m going with someone else. You can easily locate the group when you fall behind or your friends can find you if something happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;track-your-performance&quot;&gt;Track your performance&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, in the years before iPhone and apps, I always spent the evening after skiing checking the non-interactive paper panorama maps to see where I had skied. It was a good relaxation after a hard day on the slopes. Nowadays it’s much more easier to track your skiing, you just need an iPhone, an app and full battery. 
I have tried couple of various apps and my recent favorite is &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/1XOB&quot;&gt;Slopes&lt;/a&gt; ($4.99). It’s a pretty straightforward app that can be used also for backcountry skiing and it provides incomparably more information than the paper panorama map I was used to. For every run you get your top and average speed, vertical drop, distance and total time. You can also watch your performance on a very nice today widget. Slopes also calculate your burned calories and export them to the Health App. At the end of the day, it shows you a summary of your day with total distance, total time and highlights such as tallest or longest run. It’s fun to sit with your friends in the evening with a cup of tea, compare your results and performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cw2/cw2-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-get-bored&quot;&gt;Don’t get bored&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skiing alone has one big disadvantage - one can easily get bored while going uphill if you are not this kind of sociopathic chatty person. To get over the boredom I am now using &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/3IdN&quot;&gt;PeakFinder&lt;/a&gt; ($3.99). I’ve been always looking around on the chair-lift guessing which mountain is which. With &lt;a href=&quot;http://geni.us/3IdN&quot;&gt;PeakFinder&lt;/a&gt; I don’t have to guess anymore, because it tells me their names and elevation. Next time you go there with your friends you can impress them with your knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cw2/cw2-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://1perweek.com/posts/2-2015</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://1perweek.com/posts/2-2015</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
