<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rojcyk</title>
    <description>Over the past 2 years, I’ve been designing apps for various startups and businesses from around the globe. I would like to share with you what I’ve learned during the time and help you improve your products and the process behind creating them.</description>
    <link>0.0.0.0:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 16:40:12 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 16:40:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Here comes the new iPhone 6</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is the Code block we &lt;a href=&quot;http://Czechmarket.com&quot; title=&quot;Czech market&quot;&gt;iSetos&lt;/a&gt; can officially buy the new iPhone 6 in the Czech Republic. More than one month after the official launch on more important markets, but still not in the last wave. For some it might be surprising and/or disappointing that Czech market is on the same importance level as Greenland, but Czech version of Apple site with google translator style text says it all. But, back to business. I have never been fan of &lt;em&gt;queuing&lt;/em&gt; in front of the store for new iPhone, but everything should be tried. At least, there won’t be any traffickers from Eastern Europe. I expect they filled their wallets month ago and now they relax in Caribbean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It’s ten hours until the big moment, time to start getting ready.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Task one - get some info regarding the availability of iPhones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sketch a schedule for the night.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;create a back-up plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am checking couple forums and Facebook pages of the sellers and it looks like there will be probably single units of the 64GB version for sale in the whole Czech Republic. Never mind, 16GB is still OK with the iCloud Photo Library, I guess… I just hope they will have enough of them in Space Gray. Time to move to the second task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a dilemma. In total, six different stores will sell iPhone in Prague this midnight and I don’t know which one to choose. Three of them are local carriers and I don’t want to go there as they might sell only to their clients. And it won’t surprise me if they say it after midnight. That leaves three APRs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;iWant is right in the middle of Prague (the best reachability by the public transport and no parking). &lt;a href=&quot;http://Czechmarket.com&quot; title=&quot;Czech market&quot;&gt;iSetos&lt;/a&gt; is the only store that is inside a shopping mall and it brings some advantages - big parking lot and waiting inside the mall. You can also win a MacBook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iStyle is also in the city centre, but there is a parking nearby. They are the only one that communicate via &lt;a href=&quot;http://facebook.com&quot; title=&quot;Facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, therefore everybody knows they will have probably one or two 64GB versions. They will be serving coffee, giving a nice notebook with the iPhones and they will take pre-orders in the queue, so people will know whether they will get the iPhone or not before midnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iSetos is the only store that is inside a shopping mall and it brings some advantages - big parking lot and waiting inside the mall. You can also win a MacBook Pro with Retina, but we all know that the winner is always some friend of the store staff. At a first sight, this one should be the choice, but what if everyone else thinks the same?! The night will be cold and no one will want to&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wide&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/bkg.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bet you’d like more information about this sentence &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Tables&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Are&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Cool&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;col 3 is&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;right-aligned&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$1600&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;col 2 is&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;centered&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$12&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;zebra stripes&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;are neat&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;$1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;stay outside for hours. The master plan is done! At first I thought of going there (still don’t know where, though) at 8 pm, but that means waiting for 4 hours at least. I am not that crazy. Let’s have some fun before. There is still some work to do in the office, so I will reach Prague downtown just in time to watch today’s football match at my friend’s apartment. The game should end by 9 and at 10 I will be queuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;header-2&quot;&gt;Header 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;header-3&quot;&gt;Header 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;header-4&quot;&gt;Header 4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;header-5&quot;&gt;Header 5&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;header-6&quot;&gt;Header 6&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is about to start and I have also a back up plan. If it goes wrong tonight, I will try all stores on my way to Hradec in the morning. I think I should be able to find one with some iPhones in stock. I have also decided to go to iSetos, the convenient location has won. Thanks to hooligans, tha game has been suspended before the half-time. I have seen photo of three people already queuing in Brno. Don’t know whether to go now or wait. My favourite football club is winning and my time to leave is approaching&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I hope there won’t be too much people for too few iPhones. The store in the mall is still winning, it’s really cold outside.I’m here! Luckily they are making live reservations, so I know I will get 16GB Space Grey. There is something like 30 people in the line and the store still has 120 units left, d’oh! I should have come later.Still waiting, still the last in the line. Playing games on my old iPhone 5, reading and getting bored. Should have come later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wide&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/dzif.gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the BIG moment is here. I didn’t win the MacBook, bummer. They let only six people come inside simultaneously which means I will be in fifth or sixth group. At least there are ca. 20 new people behind me. Last one came around five minutes ago.I have it! My new iPhone 6! Now, it’s time to get home and get some sleep. Was it worth to wait for the midnight launch? Tough to answer… The fact is that I would be able to get one on Friday morning without any problems. But it is easy to be wise after the event, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Was it fun? Depends, I could have read at home sitting on a sofa instead of floor. But it was actually fun to organise the day, read the insider info, select the right strategy and the atmosphere was nice with lot of friendly people around. Will I do it again? That’s in Apple’s hands. If they put the Czech Republic alongside the French West Indies one month after the first launch, I will. If it will be earlier in first or second wave, I will pass. I don’t need to queue with a bunch of East European resellers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the way, Apple’s strategy with supplying memory capacities is really ingenious. Most people want 64GB version and Apple knows it. Therefore it’s the version with the most limited available units. What happens is, that 90% of the people who wanted 64GB buy 128GB, because that $100 isn’t at the end that much money. Clever!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;iWant is right in the middle of Prague (the best reachability by the public transport and no parking). &lt;a href=&quot;http://Czechmarket.com&quot; title=&quot;Czech market&quot;&gt;iSetos&lt;/a&gt; is the only store that is inside a shopping mall and it brings some advantages - big parking lot and waiting inside the mall. You can also win a MacBook Pro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Well lucky for you, I’ve included more information in footnote form. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Testing new service. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>0.0.0.0:4000/posts/iphone6</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">0.0.0.0:4000/posts/iphone6</guid>
        
        <category>test</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pragma Conference and Barcamp</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Second weekend in October was very busy with two juicy conferences taking place on Saturday. My two colleagues from Tapmates and me went to Italy to attend &lt;a href=&quot;http://pragmamark.org/events/pragma-conference-2014/&quot;&gt;Pragma Mark Conference&lt;/a&gt; while two other Tapmates members were in Hradec Králové on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.barcamphk.cz/&quot;&gt;Barcamp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pragma Mark Conference is the only major iOS and OS X development event in Italy. It is held in Milan and many community well-known people gave speech there - &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/MengTo&quot;&gt;Meng To&lt;/a&gt; (renowned UI/UX designer), &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/icanzilb&quot;&gt;Marin Todorov&lt;/a&gt; (iOS consultant and publisher) , &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ashfurrow&quot;&gt;Ash Furrow&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/marcograss&quot;&gt;Marco Grassi&lt;/a&gt; (mobile security researcher at via Forensics). Last-mentioned speaker had the most valuable presentation for me. He was talking about iOS Apps Security, which is one of the hottest topics right now. Marco showed a few current security issues in iOS apps which are facing some big Italian publishing houses, i.e. La Gazzetta dello Sport. Indeed, to avoid the panic he shared afterwards a couple of ways how the user data could be protected. One would say that such big companies know how to secure their data, but it seems the contrary is the case. Fortunately, henceforth there will be less and less apps with low security level. Another engrossing presentation was the one of Alberto López’s having talked about using Braintree payment method in mobile apps. And my developer colleagues were really excited about Meng To’s iOS Design and Prototyping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all enjoyed the conference, but I cannot say the same about Milan. I have never been there and it was the biggest disappointment for me. I know it’s the world capital city of fashion, but I thought there would be something more in the city centre than streets full of clothes stores. Of course there are the Cathedral and the La Scalla and both of them are really beautiful, but I was just expecting more of the historical heritage and less traffic. On the other hand, we tried Airbnb for the first time and it is a great way to know the local way of life and it’s a great break from staying in the stereotypical hotel rooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Barcamp Hradec Kralove was the first Barcamp event in my hometown and I am proud that &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tapmates.com/&quot;&gt;Tapmates&lt;/a&gt; were one of the partners. I have to raise the hat to the organisations of this event. They managed to bring people from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.madfingergames.com/&quot;&gt;Madfinger Games&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.warhorsestudios.cz/&quot;&gt;Warhorse Studios&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seznam.cz/&quot;&gt;Seznam&lt;/a&gt; in really short time. My colleagues enjoyed it and I asked them to pick the best one. Both of them agreed on Jiri Rydl’s presentation about Warhorse Studios’ Kingdom Come. His team spent 4 years visiting publishers who wanted to change the game in order to finance it. At the end the developers decided to go with crowdfunding on Kickstarter and managed to raise 2 million USD. I am looking forward to see videos of the presentation soom. Hopefully, I will manage to attend the next Barcamp as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>0.0.0.0:4000/posts/pragma-barcamp</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">0.0.0.0:4000/posts/pragma-barcamp</guid>
        
        <category>test</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>WebExpo 2014</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One week has passed since my first conference experience after joining &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tapmates.com&quot;&gt;Tapmates&lt;/a&gt;, so it’s time to summarise it. Going to an IT conference has never been on my wishlist, but being in the IT world now I gave it a try and went to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.webexpo.cz&quot;&gt;WebExpo&lt;/a&gt;. For those who don’t know, WebExpo is the biggest (more than 1500 attendees) internet related conference in Central Europe and took place on 13th and 14th September in Prague. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I woke up on Saturday morning thinking what the heck am I (non IT guy) going to do there for two full days. I felt like I was going to some huge geek party. I couldn’t be more wrong! I spent time listening to stuff that I was actually able to understand with information I could easily absorb. Surprisingly there were plenty of topics for people not coming from pure IT world. Maybe I was lucky, but there was only one speech that wasn’t up to my expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed the Startup Lessons section with captivating speakers (of course, Petr with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tapmates.com/&quot;&gt;Tapmates’&lt;/a&gt; story was no. 1). Having talked about their startup experience this was very stimulative and sometimes also eye-opening for those who want to build their own startup. Other stages were probably more attractive for IT guys. Topics like MariaDB or PostgreSQL were all Greek to me. However, I still had an opportunity to visit a few presentations which took my attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I would say the most interesting and entertaining was Adam Hrubý’s Design for change. Adam, an eccentric designer, had great speech about re-branding process shown on one example. On the other hand I was expecting more insider info about the real political marketing from Marek Prchal’s 20 months of continuous campaign for ANO (Czech parliamentary party). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have to applaud to the idea of spreading the conference into 7 different locations in the hearth of Prague. It was great to have a short walk between the stages near the Wenceslas Square. It gave me time to get some fresh air, process newly gained information and also grab some food (Dish’s burger truck was awesome!). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would definitely recommend WebExpo not only to IT guys but also to everyone working in IT industry. I cannot compare with previous years, but everyone around me told me that this year was the best. I have no reason not to believe them and I hope next WebExpo will be even better, although it will be a tough task to beat this year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>0.0.0.0:4000/posts/webexpo</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">0.0.0.0:4000/posts/webexpo</guid>
        
        <category>test</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
